<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Top News Online</title>
	<atom:link href="https://historyday.spprep.org/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://historyday.spprep.org/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 May 2023 00:39:47 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Three generations of Italian cinema on show at Cannes</title>
		<link>https://historyday.spprep.org/three-generations-of-italian-cinema-on-show-at-cannes/</link>
					<comments>https://historyday.spprep.org/three-generations-of-italian-cinema-on-show-at-cannes/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[paglaadmin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2023 00:30:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Entertainment]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://historyday.spprep.org/?p=13</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Italian cinema has shown its vitality at the Cannes Film Festival, with three different generations of filmmakers in the race for the Palme d&#8217;Or to be decided on Saturday. Alice Rohrwacher, 41,...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Italian cinema has shown its vitality at the Cannes Film Festival, with three different generations of filmmakers in the race for the Palme d&#8217;Or to be decided on Saturday.</p>



<p>Alice Rohrwacher, 41, represents the new guard with her third film ‘La Chimera’ that premiered Friday, a comic tale of corruption that also explores deeper themes.</p>



<p>&#8220;I wanted to make a film about connections… I show these links and explore important issues like death and the afterlife but in the lightest, most fun and stupid way possible,&#8221; she told AFP.</p>



<p>Rohrwacher&#8217;s film evokes classic Italian cinema but also points to its future, said star Isabella Rossellini &#8212; the daughter of Ingrid Bergman and Roberto Rossellini &#8212; who plays a key role in the movie.</p>



<p>&#8220;Stylistically Alice is so linked to the Italian cinema… and yet she takes it a step further and that&#8217;s maybe why we can follow her story,&#8221; the 70-year-old legend told AFP.</p>



<p>&#8220;She doesn&#8217;t use a language that is unfamiliar and yet the characters (are from) a new Italy with all these people speaking different languages living together, migrants.&#8221;</p>



<p>Rich heritage<br>Earlier this week saw the premieres of the other Italians in competition: 83-year-old Marco Bellocchio&#8217;s Vatican period drama ‘Kidnapped’ and arthouse favourite Nanni Moretti, 69, with his burlesque ‘A Brighter Tomorrow’.</p>



<p>&#8220;They all told me, &#8216;be free, look with your own eyes&#8217;,&#8221; Rohrwacher said of advice she received from her compatriots.</p>



<p>Rohrwacher, who comes from a family of beekeepers in Tuscany, won the runner-up Grand Prix in Cannes for her debut ‘The Wonders’ in 2014 and best screenplay for ‘Happy as Lazzaro’ in 2018.</p>



<p>Her short, ‘The Pupils’ was up for an Oscar earlier this year.</p>



<p>She also directed some episodes of the hit series on Netflix, ‘My Brilliant Friend’.</p>



<p>Early reviews of Bellocchio&#8217;s period drama have been positive while Moretti, a previous Palme winner, seems to have delivered more of a dud this time.</p>



<p>Weaving stories<br>The intertwining themes in ‘La Chimera’ have provoked an array of early reactions from viewers &#8212; a response Rohrwacher said she intended.</p>



<p>&#8220;Everyone sees the level they choose but they all exist,&#8221; she said.</p>



<p>Rohrwacher is one of an unprecedented seven women in competition for the Palme d&#8217;Or this year and the festival has seen many films exploring issues via the female gaze.</p>



<p>&#8220;I have always wondered if there is a woman&#8217;s language in film but I think it&#8217;s a bit more like a choir &#8212; there is family, children, grandchildren,&#8221; said Rossellini.</p>



<p>&#8220;It is not a competition,&#8221; Rohrwacher said, &#8220;women tell stories in a different way because they are used to using a lot of threads at the same time and putting them together to make a carpet, clothes, to create things.</p>



<p>&#8220;I really think we have this in our DNA.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://historyday.spprep.org/three-generations-of-italian-cinema-on-show-at-cannes/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Jason Roy ends England deal to play Major League Cricket in US</title>
		<link>https://historyday.spprep.org/jason-roy-ends-england-deal-to-play-major-league-cricket-in-us/</link>
					<comments>https://historyday.spprep.org/jason-roy-ends-england-deal-to-play-major-league-cricket-in-us/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[paglaadmin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2023 00:28:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Sports]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://historyday.spprep.org/?p=10</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Batting star Jason Roy is ending his England contract to play in the first season of Major League Cricket in the United States. The aggressive opener, who has just returned from a...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Batting star Jason Roy is ending his England contract to play in the first season of Major League Cricket in the United States.</p>



<p>The aggressive opener, who has just returned from a stint with Kolkata Knight Riders in the Indian Premier League, reportedly has an offer from their affiliated MLC franchise, the Los Angeles Knight Riders.</p>



<p>It is understood the 32-year-old has been offered about £300,000 ($370,000) for the first two seasons of the new American Twenty20 competition, which launches in July.</p>



<p>Roy was dropped from England’s central contract list last year, downgraded to an incremental deal worth between £60,000 and £70,000.</p>



<p>The England and Wales Cricket Board (ECB) said in a statement on Thursday that it had agreed for Roy to play in the US “on the proviso that he gives up the remainder of his ECB incremental contract, which both parties have agreed to”.</p>



<p>“The ECB wish to clarify that this decision will not affect Jason’s selection for England teams going forward,” it added. “We have absolute confidence and faith that Jason is committed to England cricket.”</p>



<p>The aggressive opener did not feature in England’s T20 World Cup triumph in October and November, but has held on to his place in the 50-over side and will hope to feature in this year’s 50-over World Cup defence in India.</p>



<p>The Surrey player said in a statement on Twitter that he would never walk away from England.</p>



<p>“Representing my country continues to be my proudest moment as a professional cricketer,” said Roy, who has scored nearly 6,000 international runs in all formats.</p>



<p>“I hope to play for England for many more years – that remains my priority.”</p>



<p>He added, “As a single format player with no central contract I wanted to take the opportunity to play this competition as there are currently no scheduling conflicts with England. It benefits me as an England player to play as much competitive cricket as possible.”</p>



<p>The structure of world cricket is changing at a dizzying speed, with huge salaries on offer to top players in franchise leagues across the globe.</p>



<p>Organisers of Major League Cricket are promising “six new teams and a new sport coming at the world-class level to the United States”.</p>



<p>Other players signed up include Australian stars Aaron Finch, Marcus Stoinis and Mitchell Marsh as well as former South Africa captain and wicketkeeper Quinton de Kock.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://historyday.spprep.org/jason-roy-ends-england-deal-to-play-major-league-cricket-in-us/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>IMF chief calls US debt battle &#8216;unnecessary&#8217; for world economy</title>
		<link>https://historyday.spprep.org/imf-chief-calls-us-debt-battle-unnecessary-for-world-economy/</link>
					<comments>https://historyday.spprep.org/imf-chief-calls-us-debt-battle-unnecessary-for-world-economy/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[paglaadmin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2023 00:24:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[International]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://historyday.spprep.org/?p=6</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[International Monetary Fund chief Kristalina Georgieva said Wednesday that the US showdown over government debt was &#8220;unnecessary&#8221; for the world economy but a default could be avoided. Georgieva and the head of...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>International Monetary Fund chief Kristalina Georgieva said Wednesday that the US showdown over government debt was &#8220;unnecessary&#8221; for the world economy but a default could be avoided.</p>



<p>Georgieva and the head of Blackstone, one of the world&#8217;s biggest investment funds, expressed exasperation to the Qatar Economic Forum over the spending standoff between US President Joe Biden and opposition Republicans with an early June deadline looming.</p>



<p>International markets have become unnerved by the battle as some Republicans have questioned whether a quick agreement is necessary to avert a default.</p>



<p>&#8220;History tells us that the US wrestles with this notional default,&#8221; Georgieva said, referring to past US showdowns over spending limits.</p>



<p>&#8220;At the 11th hour, it gets resolved&#8221;.</p>



<p>But she added that the Washington drama was &#8220;unnecessary for a world economy that is in such high uncertainty&#8221;.</p>



<p>&#8220;We always have to be mindful that the risk is there.&#8221;</p>



<p>Stephen Schwarzman, a major Republican donor, told the forum &#8220;it is a bit of a nail biter&#8221; and a battle of &#8220;wills and desires&#8221;.</p>



<p>&#8220;It is somewhat difficult to imagine that this is actually going on,&#8221; said Schwarzman, chairman of Blackstone which manages more than $900 billion in assets around the world.</p>



<p>&#8220;It is a political standoff. I think the two parties are about $100 billion apart on freezing spending levels. I think that could be negotiated.</p>



<p>&#8220;The whole world is watching,&#8221; added the veteran tycoon who added that he too did not expect a default but could not predict when a solution would be found.</p>



<p>&#8220;If something were to happen &#8212; really as a miscalculation on the part of the people involved in the negotiations &#8212; I think it would hit domestic constituents in the US. It would put enormous pressure to have things resolved in a few days.&#8221;</p>



<p>The IMF chief also warned that interest rates would remain high around the world because of the threat from rising prices.</p>



<p>Georgieva said headline inflation in many countries was &#8220;peaking&#8221; because of central banks raising interest rates but &#8220;core inflation, primarily because of very stubborn food prices, is still not trimming down the way it should&#8221;.</p>



<p>&#8220;Central banks have to stay the course, because, if they move back on interest rates prematurely, then tension may become a problem for growth for a longer period of time,&#8221; she said.</p>



<p>&#8220;Interest rates are high, they will stay high for longer, but we are expecting 2024, early 2025, the picture to change.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://historyday.spprep.org/imf-chief-calls-us-debt-battle-unnecessary-for-world-economy/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
