<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Entertainment &#8211; Top News Online</title>
	<atom:link href="https://historyday.spprep.org/category/entertainment/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://historyday.spprep.org</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 May 2023 00:38:49 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Three generations of Italian cinema on show at Cannes</title>
		<link>https://historyday.spprep.org/three-generations-of-italian-cinema-on-show-at-cannes/</link>
					<comments>https://historyday.spprep.org/three-generations-of-italian-cinema-on-show-at-cannes/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[paglaadmin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2023 00:30:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Entertainment]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://historyday.spprep.org/?p=13</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Italian cinema has shown its vitality at the Cannes Film Festival, with three different generations of filmmakers in the race for the Palme d&#8217;Or to be decided on Saturday. Alice Rohrwacher, 41,...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Italian cinema has shown its vitality at the Cannes Film Festival, with three different generations of filmmakers in the race for the Palme d&#8217;Or to be decided on Saturday.</p>



<p>Alice Rohrwacher, 41, represents the new guard with her third film ‘La Chimera’ that premiered Friday, a comic tale of corruption that also explores deeper themes.</p>



<p>&#8220;I wanted to make a film about connections… I show these links and explore important issues like death and the afterlife but in the lightest, most fun and stupid way possible,&#8221; she told AFP.</p>



<p>Rohrwacher&#8217;s film evokes classic Italian cinema but also points to its future, said star Isabella Rossellini &#8212; the daughter of Ingrid Bergman and Roberto Rossellini &#8212; who plays a key role in the movie.</p>



<p>&#8220;Stylistically Alice is so linked to the Italian cinema… and yet she takes it a step further and that&#8217;s maybe why we can follow her story,&#8221; the 70-year-old legend told AFP.</p>



<p>&#8220;She doesn&#8217;t use a language that is unfamiliar and yet the characters (are from) a new Italy with all these people speaking different languages living together, migrants.&#8221;</p>



<p>Rich heritage<br>Earlier this week saw the premieres of the other Italians in competition: 83-year-old Marco Bellocchio&#8217;s Vatican period drama ‘Kidnapped’ and arthouse favourite Nanni Moretti, 69, with his burlesque ‘A Brighter Tomorrow’.</p>



<p>&#8220;They all told me, &#8216;be free, look with your own eyes&#8217;,&#8221; Rohrwacher said of advice she received from her compatriots.</p>



<p>Rohrwacher, who comes from a family of beekeepers in Tuscany, won the runner-up Grand Prix in Cannes for her debut ‘The Wonders’ in 2014 and best screenplay for ‘Happy as Lazzaro’ in 2018.</p>



<p>Her short, ‘The Pupils’ was up for an Oscar earlier this year.</p>



<p>She also directed some episodes of the hit series on Netflix, ‘My Brilliant Friend’.</p>



<p>Early reviews of Bellocchio&#8217;s period drama have been positive while Moretti, a previous Palme winner, seems to have delivered more of a dud this time.</p>



<p>Weaving stories<br>The intertwining themes in ‘La Chimera’ have provoked an array of early reactions from viewers &#8212; a response Rohrwacher said she intended.</p>



<p>&#8220;Everyone sees the level they choose but they all exist,&#8221; she said.</p>



<p>Rohrwacher is one of an unprecedented seven women in competition for the Palme d&#8217;Or this year and the festival has seen many films exploring issues via the female gaze.</p>



<p>&#8220;I have always wondered if there is a woman&#8217;s language in film but I think it&#8217;s a bit more like a choir &#8212; there is family, children, grandchildren,&#8221; said Rossellini.</p>



<p>&#8220;It is not a competition,&#8221; Rohrwacher said, &#8220;women tell stories in a different way because they are used to using a lot of threads at the same time and putting them together to make a carpet, clothes, to create things.</p>



<p>&#8220;I really think we have this in our DNA.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://historyday.spprep.org/three-generations-of-italian-cinema-on-show-at-cannes/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
